Guide to the John M. Young papers, 1937-1965.
Young, John M. papers, 1937-1965.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
John M. Young papers, 1937-1965.
2851
John M. (John Mumma) Young, b.1906.
21 cubic ft.
Radio scripts, correspondence, plot synopses, notes, research for some of the scripts, and some fan mail.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Mostly radio scripts for "The Right to Happiness." Also, radio and television scripts for "Doctor Eve," "Days of Our Lives," "Attorney at Law," "Road of Life," "From These Roots," "Date with Life," "The Verdict is Yours," "Golden Windows," "The Second Mrs. Burton," "Woman in White," "Zenith," "There Was a Woman," "The Wheels of Time," "The Rising Tides," "Return of Constance Curtis," "Four Corners, U.S.A.," and the "Doris Blake Show." Also correspondence, plot synopses, notes, research for some of the scripts, and some fan mail.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Mostly radio scripts for "The Right to Happiness." Also, radio and television scripts for "Doctor Eve," "Days of Our Lives," "Attorney at Law," "Road of Life," "From These Roots," "Date with Life," "The Verdict is Yours," "Golden Windows," "The Second Mrs. Burton," "Woman in White," "Zenith," "There Was a Woman," "The Wheels of Time," "The Rising Tides," "Return of Constance Curtis," "Four Corners, U.S.A.," and the "Doris Blake Show." Also correspondence, plot synopses, notes, research for some of the scripts, and some fan mail.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Young, John M. (John Mumma), b.1906.
Subjects:
Radio scripts.; Radio serials.; Soap operas.; Television scripts.; Television serials.
Form and Genre Terms:
Scripts.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Scripts for the "Right to Happiness"
  The above scripts are numbered 834 thru 5430 but following numbers are missing: 3878 to 3887, 4151 to 4157, 4396, 4397, 4398, 4400, 4401, 4476, 4491, 4492, 4686 to 4690, 4758, 4920
  - Dec. 1942-Nov. 1944 (Box 1)
  - Nov. 1944-July 1946 (Box 2)
  - July 1946-Feb. 1948 (Box 3)
  - Feb. 1948-Aug. 1949 (Box 4)
  - Aug. 1949-Mar. 1951 (Box 5)
  - Apr. 1951-Oct. 1952 (Box 6)
  - Nov. 1953-Mar. 1954 (Box 7)
  - Apr. 1954-July 1955 (Box 8)
  - Aug. 1955-Sept. 1956 (Box 9)
  - Oct. 1956-Dec. 1957 (Box 10)
  - Apr. 1958-Oct. 1959 (Box 11)
  - Oct. 29, 1959-Nov. 1960 (Box 12)
  - Notes on the character of Lockwood - "Right to Happiness" (Box 12)
  - Research type notes on criminal law, the giving of evidence, etc. for "Right to Happiness" (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Notes, research type, various topics for "Right to Happiness," also projected synopsis of stories, Sept. 1946 LTP, copy of item Box 13, Folder 2 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- "Right to Happiness" - Monthly outlines (1950-Aug. 1955 see Box 12, Folder 15), Jan. 1945-July 1956 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- "Right to Happiness" - Long-term outlines (lacks Nov. 1945-Aug. 1946; starts Sept. 1, 1946, 15 pp., Long Term Plot Outline), Dec. 1942-Dec. 1954 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- "Right to Happiness" - Synopsis, Jan. 1940-Jan. 1944 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Script for "Doctor Eve" (Box 13)
- Script for "Empire City" (Box 13)
- Radio Misc. (Box 13)
- Script for "Days of Our Lives" (Box 13)
- Script for "Attorney at Law" (Box 13)
- Scripts for the "Road of Life" (Scripts are numbered 2895 thru 3214 but following numbers are missing: 3114), Oct. 1948-Jan. 1950 (Box 14)
- Scripts for the "Road of Life" (Scripts are numbered 3215 to 3588 but following numbers are missing: 3500), Jan. 1950-Jan. 1951 (Box 15)
- Scripts for the "Road of Life" (Scripts are numbered 3589 to 3941 but following numbers are missing: 3705-3708, 3725, 3730), June 1951-Oct. 1952 (Box 16)
- Scripts for the "Road of Life" (Scripts are numbered 3942 to 3986 but following numbers are missing: 3948, 3957, 3958), Oct.-Dec. 1952 (Box 17)
- Back scripts of various dates, Oct. 1946-Aug. 1948 (Box 17)
- Outlines for "From These Roots", 1961 (Box 17)
- Scripts for "From These Roots" (Scripts are numbered 851 thru 915), Oct.-Dec. 1961 (Box 17)
- Chapters of "Date With Life" (Numbered 1 thru 35 but nos. 12, 13, 15, 16, 19, and 20 are missing), Apr. 1956 (Box 17)
- "The Verdict is Yours" - clippings, statutes, and synopses of cases (Box 17)
- Chapters of "Golden Windows" (TV series) (Chapters 1-190 but the following are missing: 4, 5, 11, 16-20, 24, 37, 61-77, 113, 137-150, 155-158); also notes and correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 18)
- Scripts for "The Second Mrs. Burton" (Scripts are numbered 21 thru 360 but the following are missing: 22, 27, 64, 68, 191-210, 258, 336); also outlines, correspondence, etc., Feb. 1946-May 1947 (Box 19)
- Scripts for the "Woman in White" (Scripts are numbered 20 thru 378 but following are missing: 48, 60, 134, 184, 193, 201, 225, 253, 269, 316-322), 1938-1939 (Box 20)
- Scripts for the "Woman in White" (Scripts numbered 379 thru 411), June-Aug. 1939 (Box 21)
- Scripts for "Attorney at Law" (Scripts numbered 31 thru 126 but the following are missing: 63, 65, 77, 78, 122-124), Feb.-June 1938 (Box 21)
- Scripts for "Zenith" (Scripts 1 thru 14), Sept.-Oct. 1937 (Box 21)
- Scripts for "There Was a Woman" (Scripts 1 thru 5), May 1937 (Box 21)
- Notes, correspondence, etc. for "Zenith" and "T.W.A.W.", ca. Sept. 1937 (Box 21)
- "The Wheels of Time ('Of Time and Stars')"; several episodes, notes, and correspondence, ca. 1965 (Box 21)
- "The Rising Tides" and "Return of Constance Curtis"; several episodes (Box 21)
- "Four Corners, U.S.A."; notes, etc. and several episodes, ca. 1940 (Box 21)
- "Doris Blake Show"; several scripts, n.d. (Box 21)
- 2 folders of fan mail, ca. 1943-1956 (Box 21)